KENAN MAMEDOFF

IOS DEVELOPER

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

Creating iOS apps since 2013. Deep knowledge of iOS and macOS. Designed and developed multiple applications that were distributed through the App Store. Published "SozTap", a word game with online gameplay Ranked 1st in App Store Azerbaijan. Currently working at a full-time job and developing a 3D shooter game with SceneKit as an indie developer.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Swift programming language
- SceneKit, SpriteKit
- ARKit
- Core Data
- Networking
- Parsing JSON or XML data
- Unit Testing
- Core Bluetooth
- UI/UX Design
- Git version-control system
- Proficient in using Storyboards, Xibs, Auto Layout, Size Classes as well as programmatically creating user interfaces for multiple screen sizes.

CONTACT DETAILS

www.mamedoff.me contact@mamedoff.me github.com/KMamedoff twitter.com/k_mamedoff

MAIN INTERESTS

- Programming
- Xcode IDE
- Designing UI/UX
- 3D/2D game making
- Testing and contributing open source projects

LANGUAGES

- English
- Azerbaijani
- Turkish
- Russian

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS DEVELOPER, WEB DEVELOPER, UI/UX DESIGNER, IT NAVAL Limited Liability Company | 2014 - 2018

- Collaborated closely with GUI designers and developers
- Designed UI/UX for WEB pages and apps
- Created and maintained the company website and added more appealing features
- Solely responsible for creating Wordpress blog

INDIE IOS DEVELOPER

2013 - Present

- Designed and developed multiple games and applications that were distributed through the Apple App store.
- Engineered multiple custom animations, transitions, and UI components
- Created user interfaces with Sketch and Photoshop
- Wrote efficient, maintainable and reusable code prioritizing privacy and security
- Published a word game with online gameplay Ranked 1st in App Store Azerbaijan

iOS DEVELOPER

Equaleyes Solutions Ltd | 2019 - Present

- Performed technical designs and implementation of 4 complex iOS apps
- Reviewed client requirements, wireframes, and designs for technical feasibility
- Developing and maintaining applications for iOS devices, including mobile phones and tablets
- Ensuring the performance, responsiveness of applications and their quality
- Performance analyses and performing code reviews
- Running tests to identify design flaws and bugs $% \left\{ 1,2,\ldots ,n\right\}$
- Revisioning choices, software development processes, and coding standards
- Developing Nova KBM iOS app with a great team. Proud team member of app that got awarded as the best mobile banking app of Slovenia.

EDUCATION

2013-2017

Sumgait State University, Azerbaijan Bachelor of Economics

